Amit Thawait

A/4-005 Panchavati, Vijay Nagar, Andheri (E), Mumbai, Pin-400 079, Maharashtra. Mobile No: +91-8080686735

Date of Birth: 17-12-1986 E-Mail: amit17thawait@gmail.com

Title

Software developer with 3 years of experience in Ruby on Rails with a total experience for 3.3 years.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages:

- Ruby 1.9.3
- Rails 3.2.13
- Experience of web development using Ruby on Rails with MySQL, Oracle
- Experience of using SVN,
- Thorough understanding Git/GitHub
- Thorough understanding of installing and configuring plugins/gems in RoR
- Experience of using HTML, CSS and JavaScript, JQuery(including AJAX in RoR) in standards based web design
- Experience of installing and configuring RoR application (deployment), RoR
- Deployment using Capistrano.
- Deployment of applications in Heroku
- RSpec

OS/Environment: Windows XP/7, Ubuntu

Database Systems: MySQL, Oracle

IDE/Editors: Sublime Text 2, Netbeans, Aptana Studio

Experience Summary

- Experience in leading web-based development
- Experience in software development with geographically distributed teams
- Practitioner of Agile (SCRUM) and software development methodologies
- Proficient in designing and leveraging latest Web Technologies like AJAX, REST, RAILS

Educational Qualification

- **B.E** (Electronics and Telecommunication), Chhattisgarh Swami Vivekanand Technical University, Bhilai, Chhattisgarh, **2009**, **CPI**: **7.5**
- HSC, Andhra Pradesh Board, Visakhapatnam, AP, 2004, 89.43%
- SSC, CBSE Board, KV NTPC Korba, Chhattisgarh, 2002, 70.2%

Training Conducted

Year	Title	Presented to	Location	Organised by
2013	Omniauth Integration	All team members in	Mumbai	TCS
2012	Meta Programming	Ruby Team All team members in Ruby Team	Mumbai	TCS
2012	Ruby/Ruby on Rails	New members in Ruby Team	Mumbai	TCS

Career Profile

Since June 2012	Tata Consultancy Services
-----------------	---------------------------

Title P360 Navigator

Period since **June** 2012

Client Name FIRM (A Global Management Consultancy Company)

Position Developer

Responsibilities

- 1. Requirement gathering
- 2. Effort Estimation
- 3. Requirement Analysis and Design

- 4. Construction and development of application using **Ubuntu/Sublime**
- Agile/SCRUM Process Coordination, Sprint Planning, Sprint Reviews and Retrospectives
- 6. Continuous Integration of the codebase using Jenkins
- 7. Automate deployment process using Capistrano
- 8. Automated testing using Rspec and Jasmine
- 9. Deployment of Application on Com server
- 10. Infrastructure Setup of the Navigator Demo Application.
- 11. Integrate Ruby on Rails application

Project

P360° is a comprehensive benchmarking-to-implementation approach for reducing costs, raising productivity, and increasing customer satisfaction in back-office and shared services centres.

 $P360^\circ$ offers a proven methodology combined with expert support and insights from an extensive database of best practices to enable managers to rapidly formulate the roadmap for operations excellence. The results, typically achieved in less than 12 months, leads to a 20 - 30% operations improvement.

Operating System

Linux (Ubuntu 12.04)

Languages

Ruby 1.9.3, Rails 3.2.13, Javascript, JQuery

Special Software

Sublime, Github, MySQL, Highcharts, RSpec, Nginx

Project Location

Mumbai, India

Mar 2012 - May 2012

Tata Consultancy Services

Title

PCEC Reporting Application

Period

Mar 2012 - May 2012

Client Name

FIRM (A Global Management Consultancy Company)

Position

Developer

Responsibilities

- 1. Requirement gathering.
- 2. Effort Estimation by planning poker
- 3. Requirement Analysis and Design

- 4. Setup of the application in various environments
- 5. Construction and development of application
- 6. **Agile/SCRUM** Process Coordination, Sprint Planning, Sprint Reviews and Retrospectives
- 7. Automate deployment process using Capistrano
- 8. Automated testing using Rspec..
- 9. Deriving logic for PCEC Report generation.
- 10. Research and analyse available utilities for file transfer from Linux to Windows system
- 11. Creation of a task to have the disk cleanup activities so that the application server space is properly monitored.
- 12. Configuring the Autosys Agent.

Project

PCEC stands for Partner Candidate Evaluation Committee. The application generates the reports for principals which includes the financial reports and the incurred hours they have worked upon on a client engagements. It helps the committee to evaluate their potential partners for future.

Operating System

Windows 7 Enterprise edition

Languages

Ruby 1.8.7, Rails 3.2.2, JavaScript, jQuery

Special Software

Net Beans 6.9.1, Jenkins, Github, Rspec, Oracle, Phusion passenger, PL/SQL Developer, Autosys, Samba

Jan 2012 - Feb 2012

Tata Consultancy Services

Title

Staffing Tool (Enhancements)

Period

Jan 2012 - Feb 2012

Client Name

FIRM (A Global Management Consultancy Company)

Position

Developer

Responsibilities

- 1. Requirement gathering.
- 2. Effort Estimation
- 3. Requirement Analysis and Design

4. Construction and development of application

5. **Agile/SCRUM** Process Coordination, Sprint Planning, Sprint Reviews and Retrospectives

6. Automated testing using Rspec

7. Automate deployment process using Capistrano

Project Staffing Tool application helps the staffing managers to mange

projects. This helps in categorization of projects into different portfolios. It is also used to manage (allocate/ deallocate) resources on different projects along with their percentage

allocation on each project.

Operating System Windows 7 Enterprise edition

Languages Ruby 1.8.7, Rails 2.1.0, JavaScript, jQuery

Special Software Net Beans 6.9.1, Cruise Control, SVN, Rspec, MYSQL,

Phusion passenger

May 2010 - Nov 2011 Tata Consultancy Services

Title Profesional Virtual Community

Period May 2010 - Nov 2011

Client Name INDIA's Educational Institutes (SRM)

Position Developer

Responsibilities

1. Requirement gathering.

2. Effort Estimation

3. Requirement Analysis and Design

4. Construction and development of application

5. Database management activities

6. Testing of application

7. Deployment of application in various environments

Project Professional Virtual Community platform is based on

community model of collaboration. In the community, users can: Ask Questions, Answer Questions, Write a Byte - A micro blog, journal their opinions in blogs, collaboratively create content using Wiki, Share Ideas, Debate/Discuss on topics & upload and share files. Members of Community can be Institution members, Alumni, External users like Industry experts, Outside Faculties. We can have User groups as well to collaborate with other organizations/institutions in the platform.

Content like course content, web content can also be made available in the community as widgets and users can also collaborate over the content and enrich it. Every action in our platform right from inviting user to posting a blog is controlled by a security framework which ensures privacy and security of information shared.

Operating System Windows XP

Languages Ruby 1.8.6, Rails 2.3.5, JavaScript, jQuery

Special Software Aptana Studio 2.0, SVN, MYSQL, Phusion passenger

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth December 17, 1986

Sex Male

Location Mumbai

Passport Details H2643896

Raipur, 24/02/2009

23/02/2019